okay this is training session number
eight
for aaron sammy
um
let's see this here is uh
aaron this is actually 95 pounds those
are only 25 pound plates
what are you doing you can see aaron she
likes to squeeze her glutes at end range
with the um
okay there's those squats it's not
necessary
um
but i don't correct her it's not a big
deal but a lot of girls i've noticed who
focus on glutes like to do that
here's sammy dead lifting 135 she forgot
to dead lift
this happens a lot with beginners you'll
wouldn't say sammy's a beginner it's
just she's not
she's been they've been alternating
between sumo and conventional so
sometimes people forget
uh
there was aaron with a 115 pound squat
now here's sammy dead lifting 185.
uh here's aaron with now 135 this is her
uh her previous one rep max
and she sinks it right below parallel
cranks it out so it's very happy with
that
here's sammy with 225.
she's done this for three reps before
i just had her do one because i'm having
her max out today
um this is aaron with 145 so that's a
new one right max and i believe she got
parallel with it
okay here's saving now with 265 this is
a one rep max for her she's never done
this much before
so
very happy
when max's
here's erin
i told her to go deeper
and rep out with 95 pounds i think she
gets six maybe
three
so here i am with sami really trying to
get her low back arch so i've found a
lot of times if i put my hand there with
people they just keep better form
so she actually does she keeps better
form if i keep my hand there she keeps a
better arch
so that's 185 i think i had her do five
reps
sammy uh she likes to round um she's
always been that way
around a little bit she's really
stronger that way whereas aaron arches
with everything
here's aaron that's 130 though just flew
up
and cut that flew up so much i thought
she'd set a record
here's sammy this is 135 pound squat
this looks like nothing
um you can see the girls have converse
on today
i think it helped so i have her trying
185 this is 185 pounds would have been a
record conventional for aaron
but
she just barely gets it off the ground
good form that's great so fail
now here's sammy i was really happy with
her form here not much but wink going on
as you notice uh she's getting close to
parallel too this is 185 and i think she
gets three reps so
he's very happy with her form there
the forms improved dramatically now i
had aaron go to uh
this is 1 55 yeah it's 155 here
and um this is conventional
she gets uh
that third route there rolled away from
her in front of her and it really slowed
her down
um
she did it there too on rep four she
needs to keep that ball really close to
her shoes and let it scrape
scrape the shins and thighs awesome but
uh squeeze his number five out that was
a good set
keeps very good for him the whole time
and now this is a
205 for sammy
this one um
she didn't get it kind of looked very
uncoordinated and awkward
so i had her do it again
okay here's aaron
hip thrust she loves these band hip
thrusts
uh
had her do 30 reps
um
she's just cranking these out
and these
these get her glutes burning really good
um
i wanted to pause a little more at the
top
i like her going fast but kind of stick
in the top
um
i think she did 30 30
green band deep breath now here's sammy
i had to do 205 again with better form
and so she's
more smooth than she was last set so she
nails it here
maybe slightly above parallel but
very happy with her form there
uh
with samia
trying to teach her not to let the
lumbar spine tuck during these and to
keep that health that you know pelvic
tilt and lumbar arch
so she's real slow with this and kind of
um
very deliberate
but
this is a cybex squat press it's very
smooth
a lot of coaches think that this isn't
functional and it's not in the leg press
is silly
and i think that's so stupid because um
there are power lifters like
you know brandon lilly a world class
power lifter saying how he started doing
leg press his quads got bigger and his
deadlift improved this is like a
deadlift this is what the legs do in
deadlift
and it helps build the leg power you
know leg drive
um
it's a good assistance lift
andy bolton does like press he always
has he's one of the best dead lifters to
walk that he's the first guy to deadlift
a thousand pounds
um
and
the girls love leg press they feel it
working their legs so
okay here's aaron good
um
i think she gets 20 reps here with the
blue band all right um
just don't go down as far
with these bands you don't want to quite
go down all the way you want to keep
kind of
come down halfway and keep the tension
on the glutes
but uh this is aaron loves the bands a
lot more than the barbell
i think the barbell i think they're both
very important to do i like the bar i
think the barbells
a little bit better but most clients
like the bands a little more
okay here's sammy this set
she's better she um
isn't so slow
so this is three plates on each side
this is 270.
you see how tall sammy's femurs are
there
you can see these long legs these long
femurs
which is
you know why she's
part of the reason why she
doesn't always feel so coordinated with
certain lifts because of her long
femurs um
one more i think she gets
12 or 15 reps
and then here's erin
with uh now trying a blue banana green
band
she's doing good uh her last few reps i
didn't think she came up high enough but
this is really heavy for her
i think she gets ten come up higher
um two more come up higher
last one hold it ten seconds
yep i'd like her to squeeze her glutes a
little higher there but still very good
set
and now here's sammy with four plates on
each side
good form too you can see her lumbar
spine doesn't tuck at all
so she keeps good form here
and uh
cannot remember how many she gets 10
maybe
but this is four plates so what eight
plates eight times 45 is what 360.
um
she's strong of these it's her first
time doing them
go for it and then i had aaron try to
leg press this is just two plates
um
sometimes with like leg press and like
even hack squats you can
help teach people how to keep their
knees out sometimes they cave in even
with these exercises and here's aaron
again now with
uh
six plates
okay look straight ahead keep those
knees out and it's five one chance
better walk her feet
good
aaron's legs were shaking after this so
it's
this is a good exercise for her
um
don't look to this side
look straight
nice
one more
good
now
sure beat out further
yep good
and she's just cranking these out sammy
has the most end range glute strength
out of anyone i've ever trained she
always locks out the weight
good form this is just nothing for her
sami's legs are already looking more
muscular so her glutes
this was nothing for her this was a
piece of cake
and then i had her do another set with
blue and green
and she still gets like 20 or something
here
move higher
five more
see me try to i'm i have my phone in my
other hand
i try to take clips for instagram
this is a
good exercise for the girls they feel
their glutes burn like crazy and now we
move on to bench press good form this is
65 pounds
this is now looking like nothing for
aaron
which is nice because when she started
this was heavy for her
okay here's sammy with a 100 pound back
extent 45 degree hyper and it keeps it's
hitting it's like hard for her to hold
it right so i think she just gets like
five or so heavy
but uh good good form okay here's aaron
with 75 pounds one more
said this felt heavy for her today she
didn't feel real strong
so now i had sammy used 60 pounds
um
i think she ended up getting 20 yeah
as you can tell sammy's glutes are
getting more muscular already they're
starting to look about the size they
were last year
um
this is a great exercise for sami she's
always used her glutes really well with
back extensions
so yeah she gets 20 reps
now here's aaron again with bench press
this is 85 pounds
now here's
sammy doing bench
sammy looked really strong today with
bench
this is 65 pounds
trying to get the girls used to lowering
the bar lower on their chest
okay
then i had sammy do pause
this is how really how you have to be in
a competition you've got to pause so she
gets 65 for five
aaron just wasn't feeling it with bench
today so i didn't really
wasn't too concerned with going all out
she'll bounce back next week so i think
she got five positives now here is sammy
this is 85 pounds and that just looked
like nothing
so uh
i wanted to go even heavier
let's see she got three reps with 85.
now here's
aaron with 55 55 pound dumbbell
i think
uh
aaron gets
10 or 12 or something like that
aaron's glutes are getting bigger too
um now here's uh
this is um a hundred this is a hundred
pounds
so this is a pr for sammy and i actually
shut the recording off she actually got
two reps here
she got a second rep and i
my um
by my mistake i stopped recording
okay here's dumbbell military
uh 20 pound dumbbells i think
aaron gets um
12 reps maybe or 11.
and now
this is sammy using the dumbbells 20
pounders
i think yes sammy gets 12 here
she's a kind of push your head through
on the top but
i should have spent more time explaining
that to her beforehand but uh she's kind
of leaning staying lean back rather than
standing tall with it
um and then i wanted to have him try
bent over rose with the hex bar
she said i kept hitting her butt you got
to kind of row back
but aaron looked good with this this is
she had really good form as you can see
so this i thought was a good exercise
for her but then they i don't think
either of the girls liked it
um
i love doing them with these now here's
sammy but sammy doesn't have as good of
flexibility so she's more upright
but uh
still this looks good here she's not
rounding but i'd like her a little more
pandora she comes up as she
the set goes on she gets more and more
upright and now here is aaron with
50 uh those are tens so this is 65
pounds
and uh
still uses good form though
i don't think she liked these that much
though
i love doing bent over rose with the hex
bar
and then here's sammy trying it
and uh she just doesn't like these she's
being upright with them standing up and
either way that's still gonna work the
upper back
but that's it for uh session number
eight uh i was very happy got prs
i was happy with the girl's form
so a couple weeks away from the meet
thanks for watching